# Tavish Misra

10949 Spring Ave #4
Saint Ann, Missouri, 63074
(314) 712-4256
tmisra2004@gmail.com
https://www.github.com/tmisra2004

### **OBJECTIVE**

To continue to learn and develop myself so that I may be a valuable asset to the team I work on.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Troubleshooting
- Microsoft Office
- TCP/IP
- Desktop Virtualization
- Ubuntu Linux
- Windows 7
- Windows 10
- Windows Server
- Active Directory
- Java
- Spring MVC
- Hibernate ORM
- Thymeleaf
- MySQL

## **PROJECTS**

- Launchcode Capstone Project, Launchcode, St. Louis, MO, Winter 2018 (in progress) Building a personal budgeting application, called PersonalBudget, using the Spring framework. The application employs user authentication with password hashing. After the user logs in, the user may create a new monthly budget or enter transactions for purchases, which then deduct from the appropriate budget category's balance for that month, as well as delete existing transactions in the event purchases are cancelled. Users can also view and print transaction reports, as well as chart spending from month to month.
- Information Systems Design Project, University of Missouri St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, Spring 2017 Group project in which we developed a web application which tracks church members and any significant milestones in the lives of the church members, such as baptisms, confirmations, marriages, deaths, funerals, birthdays, and wedding anniversaries. Financial contributions are also tracked, including the various church funds to which the contributions are made, I actively participated in the planning, design, and implementation of the system. The agile methodology was used. My main role in the project was to design the infrastructure on which the web application would run. I used a Windows PC as the client, and a Ubuntu Linux virtual machine which ran on the PC as the server in a host-only configuration. This was done this way to isolate the system from the rest of the church network. Additionally, I deployed the Java application onto the server. I also wrote the bash scripts which launched the application server at boot time and SQL that built the database on the back end.
- Introduction to Object Oriented Programming II Project, Servlet Demonstration, University of Missouri-St.
   Louis, St. Louis, MO, Summer 2015 Wrote a simple web application (a contact form that served as a
   signup page for my student organization) using a Java servlet. It used the Apache Derby database back end
   and interfaced with the front end via JDBC.
- Personal Project, Secure Password Generator program, University of Missouri-St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, Summer 2015 Wrote a Java program (a single class) that generates secure passwords by randomly selecting characters from a string that consists of upper and lower case alphanumeric characters and special characters. It takes two inputs, an integer specifying how many passwords are to be generated and the second input being an integer specifying the character length of each password generated. The output is a numeric list of each password of the desired length and quantity.

### **EDUCATION**

LAUNCHCODE St. Louis, Missouri

LC101, Jul 2017 - Jan 2018

Completed Launchcode's LC101 program which serves as an introductory course to programming and software development. Students can start with no knowledge in programming whatsoever and in 20 weeks, students learn not only the fundamentals of programming but can build an entry-level web application as well. The course covers Python, the Flask Web Application framework, Java, and Spring MVC.

#### UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI-ST. LOUIS

St. Louis, Missouri

B.S. Information Systems, May 2017

- Management Information Systems
- Introduction to Object Oriented Programming I (Java)
- Introduction to Object Oriented Programming II (Java)
- Information Systems Analysis
- Database Management Systems (Database Design and SQL)
- Data Networks and Security (TCP/IP)
- Introduction to Information Security
- Advanced Security and Information Systems
- Information Systems Design

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Scottrade Saint Louis, Missouri Jul 2017 — Present

Service Desk Technician

Provide Tier 1 support to Scottrade employees

- Answer calls from Scottrade employees for any end user issues including password resets, account lockouts, non-functioning applications, network, and telecommunications issues, perform initial troubleshooting, and fixed as necessary
- Escalated issues that could not be fixed at Tier 1 to higher tier departments

End User Technology Intern

Jun 2016 - Jul 2017

- Provided Tier 2 desk-side support to Scottrade employees
- Imaged, updated, and installed software on new and refreshed PCs
- Reclaimed non-functioning PCs and monitors for repair or disposal
- Reclaimed PCs and monitors of employees who have left the company
- Removed reclaimed PC hostnames from corporate network and Active Directory
- Moved end user IT hardware between cubes, floors, and buildings

# **UMSL Department of Information Systems**

Saint Louis, Missouri

Student Lab Assistant

Sep 2015 — Dec 2016

- Tutored students in Data Networks and Security (TCP/IP) and Introduction to Information Security courses
- Imaged and maintained 30 laptops with the Ubuntu operating system
- Assisted professor in setting up a Ubuntu OpenStack private cloud server that students could use to practice their network administration, penetration testing, and ethical hacking skills.

Kramer & Frank P.C. Saint Louis, Missouri

Help Desk Analyst

May 2016 — Aug 2016

- Provided Tier 1 support to employees of the firm
- Responded to calls regarding domain accounts, resetting of passwords, printing, and other end user hardware and software issues
- Completed project which involved ordering laptops for the company officers and configuring them to enable the officers to work remotely via VPN.

#### **Americom Imaging Systems**

Saint Louis, Missouri

IT Support Specialist

Jun 2014 — Aug 2014

- Provided Tier 1 support to small business customers
- Answered calls from clients to troubleshoot end user hardware, software, and telecom issues
- Performed repairs, upgrades, and new installations and deployments on PCs and small business servers
- Performed on-site hardware, software, and telecom support

## **Technology Service Solutions of Missouri**

Creve Coeur, Missouri

IT Support Specialist

Apr 2013 — Jun 2014

- Provided both Tier 1 and 2 (help desk and desk-side) support to small business customers
- Provided support for Windows Server (DNS, DHCP, Active Directory, file, and print server roles)
- Provided on-site support for small business customers
- Imaged and deployed new and refresh workstations and PCs
- Performed hardware and software upgrades
- Used Labtech RMM software to monitor and maintain the network and IT infrastructure of our customers
- Managed and deployed E2 Shop System software and Sage ACT! CRM software

# Tulane University School of Public Health and Tropical Medicine

New Orleans, Louisiana

Feb 2010 — May 2010

Student Worker

- Acted as liaison between School of Public Health staff and the IT help desk
- Assisted School of Public Health staff with Moodle LMS
- Deployed end user hardware and software for faculty and staff
- Sent and received hardware for warranty repair